well, why are you communicating with me in
ну а для чего вы общаетесь вот со мной с
Russian now, uh, part of my
русским-то сейчас ээ часть моей
PhD thesis,
кандидатской диссертации
about me in my PhD, and if it's not a secret,
о я в кандидатскую а если не секрет
what topic am I using you as, uh, let's say,
какая тема я использую вас как ээ скажем
scientific
научный
material, the topic sounds a little
материал тема звучит она немножко будет
academic, it might cut you in the ear, yes,
по-академически может вам резать в ухо
yes, statistical indicators of
да ухо да ээ статистические показатели
pathological deviations in the mental
патологических отклонений умственной
activity of the population of Russia,
деятельности населения России
hello,
здравствуйте
I'm from the city of Khmelnitsky, where are you from in
я из города Хмельницкий вы откуда
Russia?
из России
I can see from your face what kind of city it is,
я вижу по лицу город какой
but I don't have a city, I have a small
а у меня не город у меня небольшой
village in Siberia near Tabos, well, what kind of
посёлок в Сибири под Табос ну какой
district
район
near Tobolsk, and Tobolsk, I got it, yeah, and
под Тобольском а Тобольск понял угу а
how are you communicating here, it hurts
чем общаетесь тут болет
people, I look, I look, what do people live with, look, you have a
на людей смотрю смотрю чем люди живут
halo of
у вас такое ореол из
stars, this is a symbol of what, but it's not there, it's a
звёзд это символ чего но он же там не
symbol of star fever, I have
Это символ звёздной болезни у меня
star fever, I consider myself a star,
звёздная болезнь я считаю себя звездой
you're a clever girl, well done,
вот ты умничка
and many people adhere to this point of view, the
молодец и много этой точки зрения
main thing is that I adhere to it, well done, you
придерживается людей главное что я её
answer beautifully, beautifully,
молодец красиво отвечаете красиво
I have intelligence, unlike the
интеллект есть у меня в отличие от
Russians, just like that,
россиян
sharply  since yes, from a
вот прямо вот так вот резко раз да от
Russian there is intelligence well thank God
россияна интеллект есть ну и слава богу
I am very happy for you I am very happy to meet a
я очень рад за вас я очень рад встретить
smart person I am sincerely happy to whom I have
человека умного очень рад искренне кму я
always reached out my whole life and how in
всегда тянулся всю свою жизнь а как на
your opinion what is the difference between intelligence and wisdom
ваш взгляд чем отличается ум от мудрости
interpretations interpretations
интерпретации
yeah yeah that is everyone has their own
интерпретации угу то есть у каждого свой
approach to defining these two things yes yes
подход к определению этих двух вещей да
I answered intelligently in your opinion or not
да я умно ответил на ваш взгляд или нет
no and how should I have answered in no way it was not
нет а как надо было ответить никак не
necessary to answer it was not necessary to even
надо было отвечать не надо было даже
ask this question no need no need to
задавать этот вопрос не надо не надо
ask but I wonder what kind of
задать а вот интересно а какой вот у вас
smart question do you have for me then I have
тогда есть умный вопрос ко мне у меня к
no questions for you
вам нет вопросов
because I am Russian and everything is clear with me
потому что я русский да и со мной всё
so
ясно так
everything is clear with you you are right you are Russian yeah well
с вами всё ясно вы правы вы русский да
your your upward eye movement
ну ваше ваше движение глаз вверх мне
helps me as a psychologist to determine that
помогает как психологу определить что
it was like this God we are colleagues
это был такой боже мы коллеги
and I am not a psychologist I am not a direct psychologist
а я не психолог я не прямой психолог
because I used psychology in
потому что я психологию использовал в
my work yeah yeah I have
своей работе угу
18 years of practice in 2 years I
у меня 18 лет практики через 2 года
will be twenty yeah well and I
будет двадцаточка ага ну а я страховым
worked as an insurance agent and therefore connecting to the
агентом работал и поэтому подключиться к
client was my main task and you
клиенту была моя основная задача и сами
understand all the consequences from here I
понимаете отсюда все последствия я
was simply forced to study it well and
просто был вынужден это изучать ну а для
why are you communicating with me with
чего вы общаетесь вот со мной с
Russian-well now it's
русским-то сейчас
part of my PhD thesis
это часть моей кандидатской диссертации
about I'm in the PhD and if it's not a secret
о я в кандидатскую а если не секрет
what topic I use you as let's say
какая тема я использую вас как скажем
scientific material Russians well it's clear yes you
научный материал русских ну понятно да
collect statistics yes the topic sounds it will be
статистику набираете да тема звучит она
a little academic maybe it's
немножко будет по-академически может вам
cutting in your ear yes ear yes uh
резать в ухо да ухо да э-э
statistical indicators of pathological
статистические показатели патологических
deviations in the mental activity of the
отклонений умственной деятельности
population of Russia uh post-covid
населения России э-э постковидный
period and how do you collect the database the topic is
период а как вы базу набираете тема
interesting and how do you collect the database in chat
интересная а как вы базу набираете в чат
roulette uh chat roulette is one of the
рулетке э чат-рулетка - это один из
channels the thing is that look the scientific
каналов дело в том что смотрите научный
method yes consists in the fact that we take
метод да состоит в том что мы берём
different samples there is a sample chat roulette there are
разные выборки есть выборка чат-рулетка
emigrants in Russia there are other
есть там эмигранты в России есть другие
others yes there is live communication that is
другие да есть живые общения то есть
emigrants in Russia emigrants from Russia
эмигранты в России эмигранты из России
emigrants from Russia you said in Russia
эмигранты из России вы сказали в России
this was a slip of the tongue yes I have people
это оговорился да есть у меня люди
who for a certain fee yes
которые за определённую плату да
conduct on-site collection of material so there
проводят на месте сбор материала так там
in St. Petersburg in Dagestan in Vladivostok
в Питере в Дагестане во Владивостоке
and then there is a comparison of these yes so that
и потом идёт сопоставление этих да чтобы
these data correlate because for
эти данные коррелировали потому что
example from these  measurements some
например из этих замеров некоторые
indicators will coincide and some
показатели будут совпадать а некоторые
will have some deviations and we already
будут иметь некие отклонения и мы уже
have scientific statistical methods
вот есть научные статистические методы
we look at this deviation due to the fact that there
мы смотрим это отклонение из-за того что
was an insufficient sample or a skewed
недостаточность выборки была или перекос
sample or this deviation
выборки или это отклонение
uh by let's say by the quality of the material yes, for
ээ по скажем по качеству материала да
example, that those who emigrated, their
например что те кто эмигрировали у них
level of intelligence may have been higher
там уровень интеллекта может был выше
than those who stayed and so on yeah but
чем те кто остались и так дальше ага а
I'm interested in
вот мне интересно а
what statistics do you consider for yourself
какую статистики вы считаете для себя
so statistically reliable you need to
так статистически достоверным вам нужно
collect for this sample what yes means
набрать для этой выборки какая да значит
yes look here it's very simple yes there are uh let's
да смотрите э тут очень просто да есть
say statistics - this is a very
ээ скажем статистика - это э очень
clear science yes if for example the population of
чёткая наука да если например население
Russia uh is estimated at 140 million yes then
России ээ оценивается в 140 млн да то
in order for us to have uh statistical
для того чтобы у нас ээ статистическая
error uh no more than 1% we need to
погрешность была ээ не более 1% нужно
survey
опросить
at least 1.48 people
1.48 человек как минимум
you know I
вы знаете я
think this is very small statistics no
думаю это очень маленькая статистика нет
for 140 million it's enough the thing is that
для 140 млн достаточно дело в том что
look then if we yes if we
смотрите ээ потом если мы да если мы
collect 1.88 people yes then the error does
набираем 1.88 человек да то погрешность
not exceed 1% in order to collect an
не превышает 1% для того чтобы набрать
error of
погрешность
0.75% we need  already 10,000 people such a
0,75% нужно уже 10.000 человек такая
small error does not make
маленькая погрешность не имеет уже
sense anymore so that is an error of 1% it is
смысла так то есть погрешность в 1% она
already sufficient for uh a certain
уже достаточна для э-э определённого
analysis that is listen to me yeah I'm
анализа то есть слушайте меня ага мне
very interested and where did you
очень интересно а где вы этому вот этой
get this statistics or rather learned this
статистики взяли точнее научились этой
statistics because for me in my
статистики потому что для меня в моём
education once there was that there are
образовании когда-то было что есть
certain
определённые
milestones that need to be achieved and then
рубежи которые нужно достигнуть и тогда
statistically there will be objective
уже статистически будут объективные
conclusions once again explaining a small number I explain I
выводы ещё раз обясня малое количество
explain so look uh I
объясня объясняю значит смотрите ээ я
graduated from the
заканчивал Киевский национальный
Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv uh the
университет имени Тараса Шевченко э
faculty of psychology the department of
факультет психологии кафедра
mathematical mathematical methods of
математической математических методов
psychology we were called yes that is
психологии у нас называлась да то есть
we studied psychology and just the
мы изучали психологию и как раз
fourth fifth year we were devoted
четвёртый пятый курс у нас был посвящён
specifically to scientific and mathematical methods and
именно научным-математическим методам и
just this number you if you may
как раз вот это число ты если вы может
know Baes was such a uh mathematician he
знаете Баес был такой ээ математик он
also has the Bats formula in
есть ещё формула батса в теории
probability theory yes he just derived these
вероятности да вот он как раз вывел эти
formulas by which you can get from a sample of
формулы по которым можно из выборки в
140 million yes you substitute this
140 млн да получить подставляешь это
number and get a minimum
число и получаешь минимум
1,488 people
1.488 людей
need to be interviewed for samples larger for a
нужно опросить для выборок больше для
larger or smaller population yes this
населения большего или меньшего да эта
sample will fluctuate you know I do
выборка будет колебаться вы знаете я вам
n't believe you for one simple reason
не верю по одной простой причине потому
because if I remember you started the conversation uh to
что если я помню вы начали разговор ээ
put me in a slightly embarrassing
немножко поставить меня в застнительное
position you called me names and now you
положение вы меня обозвали а теперь вы
want to conduct research on me I do
на мне хотите произвести исследование я
n't understand why you included a negative
не понимаю почему вы включили негативное
attitude towards the
отношение к
researcher in order to
исследователю для того чтобы получить
supposedly then objectively obliged I'll explain yes I'll
якобы потом объективно обян объясню да
explain very correctly wait stop I
объясню очень правильно погоди стоп ми
have logic in my Yes yes correct very
есть логика в моих Да да правильно очень
correct question I'll explain why
правильный вопрос я объясню почему
firstly you notice that I didn't call
во-первых вы заметьте что я не назвал
you directly I answered so beautifully
вас прямо я так очень красиво ответил
that you understood that I consider you Oh you are my
что вы поняли что я считаю вас Ах ты моя
star fever you answer beautifully and
звёздная болезнь ты красиво ответи вот и
now I'm explaining why in psychology
теперь объясняю почему в психологии
look in order for us to consider a
смотрите для того чтобы мы считали
real portrait of a person you need to
настоящий портрет человека нужно его
tease him a little because by
немножко раздразнить потому что по
default a person keeps himself within limits and
умолчанию человек себя держит в рамках и
we don't see we don't see his real portrait
мы не видим не видим её реальный портрет
when I specifically say some
когда я специально говорю какую-то
veiled nastiness yes a person
гадость завуалированную да человек
starts to get nervous internally and starts to
начинает внутренне нервничать и начинает
open up that is this provocation  this
раскрываться то есть эта провокация эта
provocation was done specifically so
провокация сделана специально для того
that you would reveal your essence more
чтобы вы больше раскрыли свою сущность
so that I would get objective
для того чтобы я получил объективный
material you know I had a
материал вы знаете у меня была
completely different method I praised
совершенно другая методика я хвалил
people and they revealed themselves
людей и они раскрывались
okay I will not show my methods
ладно я не буду показывать свои методики
and mine is not scientific well I had a
а у меня ненаучный хорошо у меня был
monetary one I needed to insure
денежный мне нужно было застраховать
people to receive an insurance premium okay that
людей получить страховую премию хорошо
is I understood correctly that you
то есть я правильно понял что вы
use people in
используете людей в
Russia to conduct your research
России для проведения своих исследований
and you pay them money for it no
да и вы за это им платите деньги нет
I do not pay you anything no
я вам ничего не плачу
no here are those who conduct the
нет нет вот те которые производят
research and yes yes this is Yes look
исследования а есть да это Да смотрите
our citizens of Ukraine yes these are our
наши граждане Украины да это наши
citizens of Ukraine who uh were
граждане Украины которые ээ были
evacuated to the territory of the Russian
эвакуированы на территорию Российской
Federation as a result of military actions yes
Федерации вследствии боевых действий да
we have for example from the
у нас есть например из Мариупольского
University of Mariupol my colleague yes a psychologist she
университета моя коллега да психолог она
conducts there yes that is she is a citizen of
проводит там да то есть она гражданка
Ukraine and we conduct her on a grant yes
Украины и мы ей проводим по гранту да
payment
оплату
and you make payment to her yes you are not
и вы ей производите оплату да вы не
afraid that she can be recognized as a foreigner
боитесь что её могут признать иногентов
well as if she is an adult she
ну как бы она взрослый человек она сама
makes the decision herself and she is hundreds you
принимает решение и она сотни вы же
are setting her up well as if You are not
подставляете её ну я как бы Вы же не
writing it down I hope well
записываете надеюсь
okay and you are writing it down I hope you
ну ладно а вы-то записываете надеюсь вам
need it  will rob and yes I
же нужно будет обрать а да я людей
write down people yes you write down people well
записываю да вы людей записываете ну
great so what Here you have
прекрасно ну и какой же Вот вы мне
not asked me a single question
что-то ни одного вопроса-то и не задали
for your so to
для вашего так
speak research how did it seem to you that
сказать исследования как вам показалось
I am smart or not cognitive or something
я умный или нет когнитивный-то у меня
else no no it did not seem that I am not smart and
или там ещё что-то нет нет не показалось
why I
неумный а почему
dont know is it innate or I dont know why
не знаю это врождённо или Не знаю почему
it is all This is a difficult question yes why are
это повся Это сложный вопрос да почему
you not smart this is already another study
вы не умные это уже другое исследование
these are other
это другие
I am not interested look I collect
я Меня не интересу смотрите я собираю
statistics I am not interested in the reasons
статистику меня не интересуют причины
why people became like this this is separate no no
почему люди стали такими это отдели нет
so I am not asking about the reasons for my
так я не спрашиваю о причинах моей
mental or perfection I am asking
умственной или совершенства я спрашиваю
about the conclusions on the basis of which you made the
об выводах на основании чего вы сделали
conclusions that I am not smart factual
выводы что я не умный фактический
material what allowed you what
материал что позволило вам какие
signs about what signs allowed you to
признаки о какие признаки позволило вам
say that I am not
сказать что я не
smart one of the first signs yes - this is the
умный один из первых признаков да - это
lack of a competent goal of the conversation you
отсутствие грамотной цели разговора вы
cannot set the goal of the conversation we are
не можете поставить цель разговора мы с
already communicating yes I am imposing the
вами уже общаемся да я вам навязываю
thread of the conversation on you you are trying to somehow
нить разговора вы пробуете как-то
parry yes but in general it is not clear the purpose of
парировать да но вообще непонятно цель
your stay here you still have not
вашего пребывания тут вы до сих пор не
voiced  secondly, uh, the
озвучили во-вторых ээ та структура
sentence structure that you form, yes, it
предложений которую вы формируете да
clearly shows a low vocabulary and the
явно показывает низкий словарный запас и
inability to construct complex subordinate
невозможность строить сложно подчинённые
sentences, that is, your intellectual
предложения то есть ваш интеллектуальный
level is simple monosyllabic
уровень - это простые односложные
sentences where there is a subject, a predicate,
предложения где есть там подлежащее
and a couple of additional
сказуемое и пару там дополнительных
members of the sentence, that is, there is no, uh,
членов предложения то есть нету вот это
complex sentences, there are no complex
ээ сложных предложений нету сложных
constructions, this is developing, yes, its not
конструкций это развивается да это не то
that you dont have it innately, yes, its just
что у вас нету этого врождённо да просто
possible that, lets say, instead of
возможно вы скажем вместо того чтобы
reading literature, you read some kind of
читать литературу читать какую-то
developmental literature, you watched TV,
развивающий вы смотрели там телевизор
read Telegram channels, and this
читали Telegram-каналы да и вот этот
process of dullness, maybe you were smart at school,
процесс отупения может в школе вы были
Im a modern indicator, Im looking at you. A person
умным я же современный показатель смотрю
can be a person, yes, he can both
я Человек может человек да может как
develop mentally and
развиваться умственно так и
degrade, you understand, that is, I dont
деградировать понимаете то есть я не
know why you are like this, yes, thats another matter, well,
знаю почему вы такой да это другое дело
according to other signs, and because, lets
ну вот по другим признакам и потому что
say, uh, you react primitively to the
вы скажем э-эво примитивно реагируете на
questions that I ask you, its clear that
те вопросы которые я вам задаю видно что
this is not from great intelligence, not from great
это не от большого ума
intelligence, well, its clear that you have
не от большого ума ну понятно вы
finished your research, it
закончили своё исследование на
turns out, yes, well, I want to ask something else,
получается да ну я по ещё что-то хотите
yes, I want to ask,
спросить да хочу спросить
yes, please, you can ask a couple of
да пожалуйста можно можно задать пару
such questions
таких вопросов
right away, I say, I will answer  as I deem
сразу говорю я отвечу так как посчитаю
necessary or I will not answer at all yes yes
нужным или вообще не буду ответить да да
yes that's the point yes I want a
да вот в том-то и дело да я же хочу
real answer yes what do you think why
настоящий ответ да как вы считаете зачем
Russia attacked Ukraine
Россия напала на Украину
Russia did not attack Ukraine oh I had no
россия не нападала на Украину о я не
doubt so there is a sign so good
сомневался так признак есть так хорошо
whose Crimea do you think belongs to the
чей Крым как считаете
Russian Federation oh look the second
российской Федерации о смотрите второй
sign everything matches damn my method
признак всё совпадает блин моя метода
works Putin is good
работает путин хороший
I don't know him personally
я с ним лично не
I can't make this conclusion
знаком я не могу сделать этот вывод
okay will you support Putin's decision to
о'кей поддержиете ли вы решение Путина о
start a special military operation yes I
начале специальной военной операции да
support three matches yes okay the question what do
поддерживаю три совпало да хорошо вопрос
you think is there a Nazi state in Ukraine
как вы считаете в Украине нацистское
or not no so Zelensky
государство или нет нет так Зеленский
I don't know personally I don't know and by hearsay I don't
я не знаю лично я не знаю а слухом я не
believe it so in Ukraine they oppress Russians
верю так в Украине утесняет русских
yes oh yes so let's have a crown like that
да о есть так ну и давайте короночка
American biolabs were in
такая биолаборатории американские были в
Ukraine
Украине
I don't know ours say that they were what do you
я не знаю наши говорят что были вы как
think I do
считаете
n't have factual material okay NATO
у меня нет фактического материала хорошо
wanted to put its bases in
нато хотела поставить свои базы в
Ukraine
Украине
here we are a
вот ми
person I can't say for Ukraine
человек я на за Украину не могу сказать
and about NATO all the more so I know that stop
а про НАТО так тем более я знаю что стоп
I know that Ukraine wants to join NATO and
я знаю что Украина хочет войти в НАТО и
this automatically implies the
а это автоматически подразумевает
installation of NATO BAS  on the territory of its
постановку БАС нато на территории её
members it is the same as you as you think
членов это же так как вы как вы считаете
Donetsk Lugansk yes go to the answer where will you
Донецк Луганск да пойдте ответку куда
send by the way dear man it is interesting
отвестите кстати милый человек интересно
we will clarify now what do you think
это мы сейчас уточним как вы считаете
Donetsk-Lugansk is
Донецк-Луганск - это
Ukraine
Украина
Dolensk-Lugansk is not Ukraine
доленск-луганск - это не Украина
five okay then look you asked
пять о'кей значит смотрите вы спрашивали
about the signs yes and I without even asking these
про признаки да и я не задавая даже этих
five key questions yes uh was able to
пять ключевых вопросов да ээ смог
determine you with my psychological
определить вас моим психологическим
experience 18 years of practice in 2 years there
стажем 18 лет практики через 2 года
will be twenty as
будет двадцаточка как
Russian and these five control
российского и эти пять контрольных
questions consolidated the result of my
вопросов закрепили результат моего
research thank you very much for the
исследования огромное спасибо за
time spent on the
потраченное время на проведённое
interview your result is one of
интервью ваш результат один из
1.88 which I met in chat roulette you
1.88 который я встретил в чат-рулетке
go dissertation
идёшь диссертация
will be like subscription comment subscribe to
будет лайк подписка комент подпишись на
y Telegram right now os vn and
й Telegram прям зараз ось вн а
popik this is very and very important youtube
попик це дуже и дуже важливо youtube
drives us through cargo ships into a shadow
заганяе нас через каргеорки в тіньовий
ban and very many videos are not shown to
бан и дуже багато відео не показуется
people  We dont always show information about the
людям вчасно не показуе інформація про
stream so that we dont have a
стрими тому для того щоб ми мали
quick connection to subscribe right
оперативний зв'язок підпишиться прям
away and theres a pop up there in the telegram where theres
зараз а попик там в телеграмі окмде ще
also some useful information and were here to
теж цікава и корисна інформація и мы
keep you up to date with a quick
повинні з вами тримати постійний
quick connection  In addition, I will
оперативный зв'язок незалежно від того
show you about this YouTube, glory to
чи покаже вам про цей YouTube слава
Ukraine, subscribe
Україні підпишись